On a sunny day, in the lab far away,
Two scientists dreamt up a wild thing.
Andres and Alan, with their heads
up high, They built a dino A.
P.
I.
Oh my!
With Neon, the serverless most grands
on the run, They changed the world!
The dinosaurs just for fun, creating
hand points for four tails and scale
title data at everyone's finger.
Tips never hit
seriously.
I have watched that video like 12
times at least, and I've laughed
every single time.
Same.
I feel like we're going to have to
start acting those out or something.
It's just the only way
to, to improve them is to
act them out ourselves.
That'll take a little bit longer
than the amount of time that it
already takes me to make those.
Oh, welcome everybody.
Yes.
Thank you everyone for joining us.
We're trying a new format.
The believe in serverless, uh, community.
We're just going through
the scientific method.
You know, we're computers
scientists, so we can say that.
So we did, we've done Zoom, we've
done Discord, uh, and now we're
gonna try, uh, what, what is this?
We're doing StreamYard.
So we're streaming live on, on
YouTube and Twitch for that matter.
I know it's going to the Believe
in Serverless Twitch, which is
new as of today that I made.
Uh, it's going to mine, which is
not new, but has zero videos on it.
So this is actually number one.
After that, it's also going
to the YouTube on the Believe
in Serverless YouTube channel.
So that's pretty chill.
Pretty cool.
Are we streaming on anything that you own,
Andres?
I'm trying Twitch.
We'll see.
I have no followers there, but let's see.
I'll check later if it
actually sent it there.
It's kind of like the first time
you write a blog post though.
It's you know, you're really just
writing it for yourself So we're
just streaming for our yeah.
Yeah, i'll watch myself 10 times.
That's fine I don't like when I watch
that video that we just that we just
played Yep Seriously, just that you're
cracking up watching it over and over
sam says it felt like I was
watching a disney musical
It's great, you know, it was
pretty
good
you guys andres.
Do you like my hat?
It's I love it.
It's it really actually makes
you look like a punk rocker.
Uh, but not with the,
with the headphones.
I feel like it does.
I
agree.
Any big plugs and there we go.
Yeah.
It was a big plug.
Yes.
Yeah.
I asked my three year old to make this for
me, but you can see the precision of these
spikes that she did not make it though.
Someone 30 years older than her
made it.
Um, yeah, you can see a T
Rex made an appearance here.
Whatever this is called, and
Lil Mo is right behind me.
Lil
Mo is
protecting me.
That's good.
We had a discussion yesterday on,
uh, the live stream that Quadra was
doing, who would win in a fight to
the death, a squirrel or a bear.
And honestly, I don't think That's
like, why was that even a discussion?
Like, there's no way
that a bear would win.
There's just no way.
I didn't catch it.
Uh, anyway, why don't you tell
everybody what we're going to be
walking through today, Andres?
Cool.
So Neon just went GA this week.
It's a Postgres serverless database.
Um, so we decided to take it for a
ride and what are we going to do?
Obviously something related to dinosaurs.
So we're going to, we're going to create a
database, populate it with dinosaur data,
and we're going to build an API around it.
So that we can do stuff with it.
So that's the high level summary.
Yeah.
Let me check something real
quick and we can be good to go.
Okay.
Let's
start.
Good
to go.
Okay, cool.
I got the dinosaur data from
a website called like craggle.
Uh, first time I've used that site.
Apparently it's a website
for data scientists.
I can't claim that it has every dinosaur.
in it, in this data set.
So I genuinely don't know how
many number, how many that is.
But it has a lot, it has a
decent amount of, of dinosaurs.
And then I, it's been a long
time since I've done, uh, data
normalization, normalization in SQL.
So I asked chat GPT to normalize
the data set into different,
into different Postgres tables.
So that's, uh, that's where
we're starting, right?
And so you're, I think we delegated
to you the responsible party
for walking us through the NEON
experience and ingesting data.
Yep.
Let's bring you,
bring you up.
So this is NEON, the NEON console.
You can see there's a free tier.
Um, I obviously set up an account.
I logged in with GitHub.
Uh, super simple to set up the account.
And you're all set.
Right.
So what we start
here is, I'm sorry, this is
the, uh, this is the web.
This is a browser that you're sharing.
Yes.
Yeah.
I guess you can't see the address bar.
I'm on Chrome.
This is, this is on the web.
So it's pretty nice,
pretty simple to set up.
So once we're here, we can see, Hey,
you're on the free tier, a single read,
write, compute that automatically scales
to zero after five minutes of inactivity.
Right, so kind of evaluating those,
the serverless aspects of this.
It's there, it turns off,
but what do you think, Alan?
I don't know.
Uh, that's, that's an interesting one.
I, what I'm actually more interested in
is how quickly it's back in available.
Like I get, I get the skill like turning
off after a certain amount of time.
That's fine.
Especially if I'm not
paying for that at the time.
Is it immediately available?
And we can dig into the docs in
a bit, see how that pans out.
Uh, and we can also just test it directly.
Hey, do you have the
pricing page available for.
For Neon, is that something
that you have access to?
Let me see,
Neon pricing.
I'm, I'm on a new tab, so I'll switch
it.
Because it is, it is listed, like
it's advertised as a serverless
Postgres service, right?
Yes.
I know, I know that answer.
I was on that website, who
knows how many times this week.
Okay.
And so, okay.
That does, can you zoom in a little bit?
Yes.
Okay,
so yeah, so we got where I'm at
0 a month, it's fixed capacity,
we're at limited data, right?
Half a gig, um, the next
year, 19 bucks a month.
Doesn't seem that, that hefty.
Uh, if you're used to running SQL server,
definitely super cheap compared to that.
Um, it auto scales, instant read replica.
So that's probably good.
So it's instantly available to read.
That's nice.
Um, it's good that they
have via marketplates.
I know that's a limitation sometimes.
Yeah.
Having that is actually, it really helps
a lot when it comes to adoption rate.
I got, uh, the, the new vendor vetting
process for a lot of companies is really,
really difficult to get approval for third
party vendors, but it's helps drastically
when it's available inside of AWS.
It's just, it hardly feels
like a new vendor because it
goes in and gets rolled up.
The costs get rolled up in your AWS bill.
And it helps for
like big org budgeting, right?
Usually if you're working with AWS
already, you have a big partnership
with, uh, some spend in AWS and all that.
So you can bundle up that in your
AWS spend when it goes through
the marketplace, I believe.
So that also helps, uh, bigger orgs.
Yep.
And obviously we got the last option,
which is call us and we'll figure it out.
That's normal, normal, but
this, like the pricing plan here
don't feel serverless to me.
A lot of people, you know, you and I
gave a session for believe in serverless.
Like it was like the second one ever
talking about what serverless mean.
And one of them was pay for what you use.
And these don't really look like that.
That's especially when,
like, I don't even know.
Can you click on compute hours?
What does that mean?
What's a compute hour?
Compute hours, the metric.
or compute usage in NEON.
The quick math, compute hours
equals compute size times
hours your compute runs.
Each pricing plan includes a
certain number of compute hours.
How quickly you consume these
hours depends on the size of your
compute and how long it runs.
It's I feel like it's saying the same
thing over and over, which is fine.
Once you exceed the allocated
amount of hours, you'll be billed
for overages in a given month.
OK,
it's like a phone plan.
I know it's doesn't say is it
is it priced at the same rate or
do you get like AT& T and then
you'll get charged a ton of money?
Yeah.
Interesting.
There's a lot.
OK, this is the FAQ for
the for the pricing.
OK.
Yeah.
So plan comparisons.
I want to see if they have pricing
metrics that feel serverless.
Can I just do the free tier?
A lot of times when you see, when
you see tiers like this for something
that's added as serverless, really
what you're paying for is, uh, support.
It's the, it's the general
support tiers that you're paying
19 a month for, 69 a month for.
So I'm curious if it has at the
bottom, like what, how much a compute
hour costs, how much, how much it
costs for a gigabyte of storage.
Does it have that down at the bottom?
Maybe in the
FAQ.
Let's go throw it all the way down.
We might have to look at the docs later.
How is storage?
Do, uh, storage.
Expand the one that says, how
is storage charged in NEON?
I'm actually curious about that one.
It's the third from the bottom.
Neon implements a unique storage
engine that enables database
branching on copy on write.
Database branching on, gosh, I said
it twice and I still don't understand.
So the cool thing, and we will dig
into the branching thing, but it
seems like if you branch 10 times it's
not going to Duplicate your storage
costs, um, which is interesting to do.
It says storage from Neon.
So Sam is helping us out.
He said that each plan has a
different rate for storage.
Oh, I guess that's good.
I guess that I would almost consider
that like a volume discount when
we're talking about paying more.
Yep.
Notifications.
Yeah, I'll keep this one open.
Cool.
It's interesting.
So how do you feel around
the serverless flag there?
So I am going to, uh, I'm, I'm
going to hold a Switzerland.
Right now and I am going to say I'm
not going to make a judgment yet.
So right now we're gonna say
It's
kind of serverless I'm not gonna say
it's definitely not it definitely
doesn't pass all the tests right now on
my first impression But I'm also going
to give it the benefit of the doubt
and not say no at this point in time So
we're gonna leave it at kind of Yeah,
it definitely feels more serverless
than other RDBMS offerings, right?
So there's definitely a very different
approach here, but is it true serverless?
Uh, Yeah,
I'm of the strong opinion that
serverless is, uh, you know, it's
a set of capabilities that that's
really what, what that whole thing
is ready to use right off the bat.
No instances.
You're not creating anything.
Everything baked in by default.
And then you don't have to worry
about scaling and all that fun stuff.
Okay.
So let's, uh, let's stop our
tangent and go back to what
we were supposed to be doing.
Ah, what is this?
So I'm going to be creating the projects.
I'm going to call it Dino land.
Uh, right now in the free tier, it allows
you to do one project, one free project.
So there it is, and I'm going to, nice,
I like the music, Alan, so Dino API.
Let's just call it Dino DB.
So pretty simple setup.
I haven't actually
explored, but just like Git.
Uh, so they claim the branching
strategies for databases.
Or database data.
So you can change the branch and they
defaulted to main, which is cool.
I hadn't expanded this yet and
you can select a version of
Postgres, so I'll just do 16.
Might as well do the latest, right?
Yeah.
Why start in the old stuff?
Cool.
Couldn't even tell you how
to write a Postgres query.
Is it just regular SQL?
It is.
It's okay.
I can do that.
I remember I struggled because I
haven't done SQL queries in a while.
So I had to, uh, well.
Looking into this, I did, uh, Google
some queries, so you can get a sense
of my SQL, uh, SQL abilities right now.
Oh gosh.
Especially if you call it
that you're at a good bar.
I remember the very first time I had
ever opened SQL server management
studio, uh, had the architect on
my team standing over my shoulder.
This was like, I don't know, maybe a week.
On the first job that I had
straight out of college.
I didn't take any database
classes in college.
It wasn't required and he
said, click on new query.
So I clicked on new query inside of, uh,
inside of SQL Server Management Studio.
And he says, okay, select
star from any pause.
And I am looking at the screen
and I'm looking for literally
anything that says select or star.
And I was like, what do you mean?
What select star from what, what
am I supposed to be clicking on?
And he's like, no, no.
And then at that point, it's kind of
the, the horror sinks in on his face.
It's like, what, what have I done?
I just hired this guy and he said,
it's not, not my proudest moment.
I'll, I'll
say
that.
Okay.
We got a connection, uh, assuming this
is the way you connect with Postgres.
Again.
Make this clear.
Neither Alan or I have ever
worked with Postgres before.
So it should be fun.
We work with SQL, but five, six, how
many years ago, Alan, since we made
the move to the cloud and DynamoDB
mostly, I assume it's going to be like
riding a bike.
I mean, I have, you know, Eight
years of experience doing that is
like a serious part of the day job.
We'll see.
So you can create a pull connection.
I'm not going to do that.
So I copied this connection string,
see what other options it gives me.
Okay, it gives me Oh, it
didn't expose the password.
Cool.
Okay.
So I'll do the PSQL.
You can do get the next node.
I'll probably send you the node, Alan.
Is that using there?
Oh, nice.
Sweet.
I hadn't
seen this.
Okay.
Actually, you know what?
I am kind of surprised that this
code, it's just using Postgres.
There's not like a, a neon.
Yeah, it's, so what I saw, there's
a, there's a Neon CLI, it's Neon CTL,
uh, Neon Cuddle, I guess, uh, Neon
Control, and then there's Postgres.
So you're dealing still directly with
Postgres, it seems, while doing stuff
from your terminal and whatnot, um,
as well as with, within the code.
Do you want this?
I can send it to you, Alan.
Yeah, we have the, don't we have a
live session up in VS Code already?
Paste that in there.
Oh, that's true.
You'll, people are not going
to see that in the screen.
Not yet, but we're not, we
don't need to, to be there yet.
So let's go.
Yeah, there you go.
Okay.
So you got to here because you
just created a new project, right?
It was a new project.
And yeah, new
project.
I created the database and now it gave
me the connection strains and now it's
giving me all these examples of how I can
connect to the neon Postgres database.
That's really nice.
I like it when, when companies do that.
So there's several, the tool I installed
in preparation for this is P S Q L
uh, well, I guess it's just Postgres
as well, but I just have a CLI.
So I got this connection strength.
Before you close this, I wanna see,
there was an option at the very
bottom that said serverless driver.
Neon serverless driver.
Okay, so they have, ooh,
okay, I'll send you that too.
This is what I wanna use.
I wanna use this one.
Yeah, I'll get that one.
I'm gonna, okay, yeah.
I just broke a linting
and everything, it's fine.
And there's websockets,
okay, I'll send this too.
We'll see how we use these,
but just to have them at hand.
I'm assuming we can bring
them up again at some point.
All right.
Yep.
Uh, so HTTP, WebSockets.
Did you choose a region?
It's US East
1.
I can see that in the connection string.
That's why I was asking.
I didn't know if you chose that or
if that was like an implementation
detail that we stumbled
on.
So question here.
Do you think it's going to expose
the password on the dot EMV?
Yes.
Oh, I thought, oh no, it isn't.
It isn't.
Okay.
There we are.
I'm just copying it.
And I'm going to paste it so you
can put it in an EMV file in the
background now with the password.
They're protecting us!
That is nice.
And that's good.
Like, here's a question from Sam.
Is this a public facing database?
Uh, I think so.
I think that's like the
nature of this kind of thing.
Yeah, it's there.
I mean, you, to connect.
You need the password, but it would
be, I I'm assuming you would be able,
if you find the host and the database,
you would be able to do some stuff.
Um, I do, and we'll get back to your
question because I think there's
some stuff connection stream.
Okay.
So let me just copy this
one, a storage fault.
So they're really making
emphasis on security here.
And that's nice.
I actually liked that a lot.
So I'll do this later.
So this is the, the dashboard.
Yeah, it's the dashboard.
So that has
usage metrics in here.
Yeah.
I was looking at that
yesterday.
Uh, so there's monitoring as well, I
guess, to see your CPU and all that.
If I go back in the billing, you see
how much you've used of your free tier,
or maybe if you're in a paid tier, it
seems to have more information there.
You can see how many branches.
Which very interesting topic.
We'll, we'll play around with
that, but here, if I go to billing,
here's the message built into here.
Cool.
Okay.
Yeah.
But I'll go back to projects.
Dinoland when I created the project,
Alan, it lets you choose which region.
I did not see which ones it
gives you the ability to select.
But obviously I chose the most
stable region in the world.
It's US East one.
Uh,
it's definitely the most
used region in the world.
And you have your primary branch
and this is idle, I guess, since
we haven't done any reads, uh,
we'll get a cold start when, whenever
we hit it for the first time, I like
that status on there, it doesn't
feel serverless to me, honestly.
Having a status like that, like an
uptime status or like an up status.
Fine.
So we already have data.
Oh, you've already
loaded the data in here?
No, but we already have
consumed something.
Cool.
So first step I want to do
is create the tables, right?
And as Alan mentioned, we, we use
AI to generate some, to get data.
And then we got the queries
to generate the tables or the
commands to generate the tables.
One cool thing we have
here is the SQL editor.
right in line.
Uh, it keeps a history per project.
That's what I saw while
playing around with this.
So I'm not going to go with the
basic, you can save queries here.
So it's kind of like your
SQL management studio, uh, or
equivalent of whatever you use.
So I do.
Have you
used glue before?
I have not,
or I guess it's not glue.
It's Athena.
Reminds me of that.
Okay.
Yeah.
So I'm going to copy.
And we'll just talk about the commands.
How does this look on the share?
Alan?
Okay.
Yeah, it's definitely okay.
So we're creating a period
table for the time period.
They lived and their location, taxonomy,
naming, species, and the actual
dinosaur with all the references, right?
So we can see if you're a
Postgres user, this should be
your normal, your normal stuff.
I could run this from a terminal on
my machine or just directly here.
This I'm just going to do here directly.
You can see it identified six queries.
I wonder what the explain does.
It's detecting a syntax error, but
this actually, this actually worked.
So let's run it.
Yeah.
So I'm just going to run it
because the query completed.
Right.
And, and here it's kind of the
six queries that identified.
We can go, if it was six selects,
we'll get them all here and see
the results for each of those.
That's nice.
It also has the
milliseconds it took
for each one of those.
Which I assume all those add
up to those compute hours.
So let's go back to the dashboard
and see what, what happened here.
Right.
Um, I'm not sure how immediate
a cloud watch it lags.
Yeah.
So we'll wait a second.
These
are also what we're doing control
plane operations versus data plane.
So we're creating tables.
We're not, I'm not going to round with
data, like fetching and adding in there.
So it probably wouldn't show up in there.
So yeah,
let me go back.
Okay.
So I got the dashboard open.
So if I go to tables, we
should see these, right?
Yeah.
So here they are, uh, dinosaurs
query queries while I click this.
So be careful with that.
If you're in the free tier
and you introduce the big
table, uh, Buh, buh, buh, bum.
Cool.
So we have all the tables
here that we defined and an
interesting thing here, right?
You can see it's main.
It just feels very Git, GitHub like
that there's kind of branches here.
And I think that's, I don't know
if the main selling point around
this as well, uh, other than the
pricing serverless y kind of thing.
So these
are data branches.
It's not code branches,
it's data branches.
So you can fork the data as it exists, run
your ETL jobs on it to make sure that it
works and actually do something with that.
That's
pretty neat.
So let's do that.
I mean, I can, let's do a
branch, uh, and that's where I'm
going to load the data, right?
So we have the tables there.
Let's create a branch and let's
just call it and more depth.
I'm already signed in.
Leave me alone.
So just like when you're creating a GitHub
branch or a Git branch, it's from where
this is the parent, which is the primary.
And I'm creating one called, let's
just call it DinoLin and Dev.
And you can select a
specific point in time.
So that's interesting too.
I want last month's data just right now.
So let's just do current point in time.
A read, write will be created.
To connect to this branch from any client.
Okay.
Hey, read, write,
compute.
I feel like there's a word missing there.
With size 0.
25 will be created.
I does that mean that it is having
halving the capacity units that from
the main branch, the support, this one,
it seems like it, because what do we
have on the main, I mean, this is read.
Oh, maybe it's not, maybe
it is just a new order.
Cool.
And they mentioned, right,
they, they have GitHub actions.
They've built, you can call the API
directly, or like I mentioned, neon CTL.
So I could have created the
branch from the terminal, but
I like that they have a
GitHub action for this.
Cause that means you could
run like, you could run really
good CI tests on your data.
You could, so you remember
most of our issues with CI CD and
running automated tests, um, like this.
contract test and all that with
seeding data for it to actually work.
And we have manual steps to
make calls to see the data.
You can just have one branch preceded
that you either branch off of for
your CI CD and then kill at the end.
So you don't, you can even run this
on a, like a production level thing.
Uh, but you're not affecting the real data
because you're branching out the data.
So that's pretty cool.
Oh my
gosh.
I love that.
Yeah.
You could even have a branch that
has just your test data in it.
And then branch off of that one every
time, uh, A GitHub workflow run.
Or even trying to reproduce an issue
with client data, but you don't
want to affect their real data.
You branch out of their data.
And then just start working out of it.
I don't know how compliant that would
be, so don't quote me on that yet,
but depend on your compliance needs,
you might be able to do that or not.
I need to get like an approve button
that we can put on, on this show that
just puts like a big check mark or a
thumbs up right in the middle of the
screen because that's pretty awesome.
Yeah, really, really like that a lot.
It's a lot of value to that.
Uh, I did not read this as always, Alan.
We'd never read the docs and we'll
be complaining after seven days.
Where did my data go?
Um, it will not increase storage until
you're start making, or it ages past
your history retention window seven days.
So nothing affects the parent.
Cool.
So I'm going to create this branch, gives
me another set of connection strings.
So I think before we start actually
building the API, we'll build it off
of main, the things I already sent.
So we'll see a little bit of it.
So I'll copy this and I'll
try to not expose my API key.
I'll see if I can, I'll see if I can.
So as I'm doing this, I'm going to
run on a terminal here, PowerShell,
and I'm going to connect to this
and hopefully I can hide it somehow.
Maybe not because it's going to
expose the, we'll just go with it.
So now
what are we doing right now?
I was created the connection and a
terminal to see if I could not expose the
secret, but we'll, we'll flow with it.
Uh, so I'll switch the
screen to the terminal.
Well, we're now just going to use PSQL to
see the data that we have in CSV files.
So let me just show a little
bit of the docs here, uh, that
I was navigating wrong window.
So neon.
Import CSV data.
So they have different ways to import.
I'm assuming these are standards,
Postgres, uh, ways to import, but, um,
since I haven't used it, I don't know
who is it from, but it seems this copy
thing from CSV seems to be a standard
Postgres thing, uh, which is pretty cool.
Uh, it just does it if you had the
right to limiters and titles and
your, and your things, it just works.
They have multiple imports.
It was just from Postgres, from
a Neon project, CSV, Heroku,
AWS CMS, and from MySQL.
So that's cool.
Or just sample data.
What we're going to use is CSVs
that I already have locally.
So I'll switch it to that.
Let
me stop this screen, share my window
and non windows users.
I'm sorry, but I'm a windows user.
So you know how to, okay, there you go.
Is that good enough?
Cool.
So.
Again, so we don't spend the
whole session trying to figure
out how to get data in there.
We have the files with the CSV and
like I said, it's pretty simple.
So right now I'm porting the
species, so it's just copy to
the species table from the CSV.
And I wish I had, um, known what this
does, but I didn't research that.
So we'll just go with it.
The delimiter is a comma
and the CSV header thing.
I don't know what that means, but
it just, that means that that means
that the CSV file has a header row.
Okay.
That's simple enough.
So here we copied 309 records into
that database and I'll just keep going.
Right.
So we'll go back to the,
the console in a bit.
So now I did taxonomy.
We have period, 154, naming.
This is fast.
Yeah.
And the actual dinosaurs, we have 309.
Yes, that's definitely not an
exhaustive set of dinosaurs.
There's just no way.
I don't know enough about dinosaurs to say
with 100 percent certainty, but I'm like
98 percent sure there were more dinosaurs.
There's
two.
I don't know of more.
Okay, let me switch back to Neon.
So we can see the data actually
there.
I want to see the usage metrics on this
one because you just put in, I mean,
I can't say it's a ton of data, but
you did just put in a decent amount,
you know, it was over a thousand
records across seven, seven tables.
So let's take a
look at that.
So yeah, I'll go back here.
So this has its own thing.
I guess you can track this.
I'm refreshing.
Wow.
That looked terrible.
So the parent active time, very minimal.
It doesn't show anything yet.
Then down here.
It might be lagging a little bit.
Yeah,
but we still don't see anything.
Oh, there's
data points.
I
saw them.
Yay!
So we got RAM, 122.
VCPU, 01.
Allocated, 25.
Can I do like a close up?
You can't like drag over that?
I guess on this view we could.
Let's see.
Nope.
Used to, but okay.
Okay.
So we've got the low spike.
Yeah.
And I guess this is the data
allocated versus used to allocate
it as the, the black bar there,
and then the blue is our usage
buffer.
Okay.
So there, it has a cache, I guess,
built in and active connection 12,
26, 10 minutes ago from the terminal.
Cool.
So how many rows?
Look at that.
Inserted, updated.
I don't know where the updated is
coming from because I have not.
Okay, let's keep going.
So now if I go, let's go
to tables and main, right?
So if I click on dinosaurs,
we don't have any data.
But if I switch the branch
to dev, there we have it.
So that's Ardenyx herbivorous.
So now we could.
Actually write queries.
I'm assuming you can select the branch.
Yeah.
So the branch is here.
So if I, is there a new query?
Yeah.
So if I do it, so I'm not going
to do the all caps, select all
from dinosaurs pronounce it.
Cause I always spell it wrong.
So here it is, right?
Just your standard sequel.
Uh, we could even do, let's
see if I don't mess this up.
Inner joins species.
Dinosaurs.
speciesid
There's no easy way.
I can't actually go to the right.
So I have to do that
would have been very nice here.
It has some, but it doesn't.
Right.
So you can see it, it recommends
based on what you already have.
So species dot species ID.
So there it is, but it's
because I already had this.
Yeah, it did say local
where it was coming from.
Let's see if this one explains it.
Oh, okay.
As interesting as that is, I
actually want to point out that
Mark looked it up and there were 700
known species of extinct dinosaurs.
Oh, wow.
It's interesting
that it says extinct.
Are there non extinct dinosaurs, Mark?
I'd say crocodile, I guess.
And if you believe me.
Hey, I can't really read that.
Can you, can you zoom in?
This is,
so it's looking at the inner join,
both tables that are joined and
I guess finds relevant records by
sequential scanning, so it's just
explaining all the stuff it does.
Okay, cool.
It's the execution plan.
The cost is that's cents,
dollars.
That's scary, but I hope that
was not a 7 and nine cent query.
Yeah.
So I clicked this was explained there's
raw data so you could process this
however if you're a Database guru, you
can probably do a lot of stuff with this
I am definitely not close to being one
so I don't know really how to read this
But there's a lot of information here
that you could use Let's try the analyze.
Was that the analyze?
Explain and analyze seem
to be doing the same thing.
So We'll have to figure
out what the difference is.
So, but now if I run it, we get
that and the species, so we can
do Dino, sars name, comma species.
Species name I think is the,
yeah, intelligence would be
great,
but we got the, it has the
schema, so it should be able to
provide some sort of intelligence.
Um, so we got here, right?
Uh.
I'm going to blame ESL here.
I can't pronounce any of these.
Uh, Oh no.
Even if English
is
your first language.
Uh, kilobater.
He's gigantic, gigantic, cool.
So we have them all here.
Um, let's see the operations piece.
I guess this is kind of like
a cloud trail kind of thing.
What has happened in your project around.
The database, not so
much queries, it seems.
So you can see when it
suspended the compute.
Let's look at the dashboard
now that we ran some queries.
And you can see here's the
history of all that I've done.
So that's cool.
But I'm gonna just trigger
this a few more times.
Hopefully I don't run out of free
storage or compute or anything.
But if I go to dashboard,
let's go to the full monitoring.
Yeah, if those were immediately available,
I would be like extremely impressed.
I mean, they're pretty, it's pretty
near real time, but not how far
are we lagging behind two minutes?
Probably.
That's not bad.
The blue is, okay, updated
database size, that's going to stay
relatively flat for the rest of this.
It does seem to be running
update operations every time.
And I'm wondering if it's trying to
update some sort of like metrics or
analytics tables that we can't see.
That might be, those should probably
be excluded from your metrics because
those are not, they shouldn't be
charged to me if that's the case.
Uh, because that's operational for Neon.
It's part of the, the
subscription price, I guess.
Uh, so the main is idle.
This one's active.
So now I wonder, I haven't tried
this, but can you just merge a branch?
Branches.
You can set it as the primary.
I don't know that doesn't seem
like the right command though.
Green name set as protected.
What is this bro?
You reach your limit for protected.
Oh, guess I guess this one's protected.
Yeah, I like it.
You want to protect your main branch.
Yeah,
but I would think that's it's
the other way around, right?
I want to.
Let's see, open this.
I don't want to create a branch.
Go
to the dev branch from in here.
Let's get, look at the detail view.
This is where I would expect
it to show up under more.
It's the same thing.
Compare to parent.
What happens if you do compare?
Oh okay,
like, like a pull request?
Gamers are in sync.
Click on compare.
Let's see if that does anything.
No, I guess if you
change this then compare.
Well, it's not comparing the
data, it's comparing the database.
It's schemas.
Okay, interesting.
So I'll go back to the
main and populate that one.
We haven't changed the schema,
so we'll just ignore this branch.
I thought you would be able to
merge the data from the branch.
That would be cool, but it's
weird now that I think about it.
So
It looks like what it's done, this
is just complete speculation, Um, it
has a compute, a table for compute.
I really don't like saying it like that.
Go to your branch.
And if I had to guess, my guess
is that that is a, no, no, no.
Don't look at the data.
We were just looking at
comparing the branches.
Go back to the branch.
Oh, I see.
And
then click on dev
here.
Yeah.
So you see it computes down there.
I'm guessing that's some sort of
EC2 instance under the covers.
Oh, what happens if you click connect?
What is that going to do?
Uh, so it shows the connection details.
Yeah, maybe I'm wrong.
Okay.
You have roles.
What is this?
Okay, I wanna just do something very
quick and I'm just gonna copy this create
table and I'm on the dev branch so I'm
gonna do a new and let's just do two.
Right, just to see a comparison
on the branch comparison.
Query completed, we should see,
maybe not.
This is what you call eventually
consistent right there.
Well, I don't know, does that, no,
you're looking at the main branch.
Ah,
big guy, good catch.
Okay, so here it is period two.
So now if I go here, how did we
compare uh, you went into the deck?
Yeah, there you go compared to parent.
Let's see what it shows here.
It shows the change and
look at this sequence
What would you do with this?
anybody anybody who's Anybody who
knows that's watching, can you please
tell us what you would do with this?
It looks like it's a handoff to you.
Like, to me, this looks like a change
script that it says, here you go,
run this, and you're going to be,
uh, up to, up to the latest with your
destination branch.
But yeah, you can, yeah, what we
saw, you can't merge back up, right?
Even the schemas.
That's what I'm saying.
Like here's, this is the handoff.
This is the part where I'm not
going to do it for you anymore.
It's you're on your own.
So my best
effort.
Yeah.
Okay.
I wonder if you put data.
So let me populate the main branch.
We'll have data and we can start
hooking it up with, uh, SDKs.
Do you want to keep navigating
a little bit more here or want
to play around with the SDK?
I feel, I feel
pretty good.
If there's anybody watching that wants
to do something else specifically,
uh, Speak now, otherwise we're going
to go and actually build an API.
Cool.
So let me get this
connection and I'll populate.
Let me, I'll do this in the
background and keep track.
If there's any questions of anything
someone wants to see out on yes.
So let's see if it remembers my commands.
Ooh, nice.
Okay.
One
doesn't remember anymore.
Period, naming,
location, and dinosaurs.
So now for main, if I go and query here,
I'm on the primary, and do this query from
primary, we should have some data now.
Cool.
So main is populated now, Alan.
Okay, great.
So we're, we're good to go then.
For actually trying to see
if we can get it to work.
Yes.
From the SDK, right?
We know it works within their
console and there it is.
So now let's play around with the SDK.
There's CLI, so we can
actually try that too.
Um, let me open the live share.
Can you see me there?
Yeah.
So it
looked like there's two
things pasted in here.
I don't know.
Exposing my secret, Alan.
What am I?
Why, why were there
environment variables then?
That's annoying.
Yeah, that's, okay.
Sorry I've been exposed several times.
That is weird that it, yeah, okay.
Okay, so this is what I sent to
Alan based on the kind of the
connection strings that it gave us.
So there was a serverless option,
which seems to be a NEON database,
uh, npm package for serverless.
And then there was the other one, which
is just a plain Postgres, uh, package.
Right, Alan?
Yeah.
Yes.
I put that one, I put the regular
Postgres package in a different file.
Cause I want to use this SDK.
Cool.
So two methods here then that
we can use both look like
they're ripe for SQL injection.
So why not?
Right?
Nobody.
I mean, who needs to know?
SQL injection.
When you have the direct access
to the database, it's fine.
Okay.
Uh, do you have a preference
for which way?
So these two options it gave you,
these are the two options that it
gave, you know, one is it feels
much more raw than this one.
I don't even know what the word would be.
Not raw.
Okay.
I like the fine process.
I don't know.
That's right.
Well, but
we don't have a pool, right?
We did not create a connection
pool, so that wouldn't work.
So I think it's the first one we need.
Okay.
Let's see if this works.
Node.
API.
That did not work.
Can't use import statement.
Okay.
Make it MJS.
Just make the file MJS.
Don't go back in time, Alan.
Let's make it ECMA.
Well, no, but the Lambda function
is probably going to be common JS.
So let's just keep it.
Do what you were doing.
Do require.
I am just ha Oh, there we go.
This is what I was looking for.
And then it's just equal require.
There you go.
Okay,
hopefully this will fail, I
guess, slower than before.
Okay.
Oh, this is not async.
That's fine.
We're nothing if not flexible.
We're engineers, right?
Yeah,
we're used, we're used, uh, to fail.
Don't you have to await the run?
Ooh, look at that.
There's a query.
It worked almost at the first time.
Look at
that.
I'm going to count that as a first time.
I, yeah, I will, because it's the first
time we actually were able to call
all the SDK, so that to me is good.
Google.
Okay.
Let's filter that, we're
just gonna have fun with it.
Uh, oh gosh, I don't
remember the syntax for this.
Is it It's like,
I think it's like that.
But is diet, diet's not a
I don't think we call it
name.
It is?
Okay.
But I'm looking at it
right here in the terminal.
Oh,
there you go.
Column.
So where, and this is where the
wheels fall off, where we're actually
trying to not use the generated code.
Oh, we're on a run.
We have to write the code.
Now it's all going to fail.
Okay.
I just had to switch.
It didn't like the double quotes.
So we switched to a single quote.
Uh, okay.
So there
are.
Jonathan has taken failing slower than
before as his whole life motto now.
So when the manager says fail fast,
you're not, you're not going to do that.
Let's just fail slower than before.
Okay.
Let me do this real quick.
Just so I can get this connection
string off the, off the screen.
It's fine.
I mean, it's, I'm on the free tier.
The worst that can happen
is someone gets in there.
Hey, buddy.
Waste all our CPU and we
can't keep going with the,
okay, so let's do this then.
Um, let's, let's make it an
API that we can run locally.
Okay.
And then let's set that up.
Yes.
Good old express.
Okay.
And then, Hey, uh, we'll do.
I love Code Whisperer so much.
Okay.
So we're going to get, I'm
trying to remember the syntax.
I think it's curly brackets in Express.
We'll see.
Okay.
So we will do, I guess I should move
this out globally and then we will.
Parameterize it in a bit.
Const dinosaur equals.
Okay.
So we have that.
Now we're just going to do this.
Checking routing posts equals
await select their where diet.
No, not diet.
It's name, right?
Is that the, is that the name
of our, let me check the field.
It is just name.
Yeah.
Okay.
We'll do that.
We will string interpolation and then we
will.
And yeah, we'll just accept
the inputs from anybody.
Uh, that's fine.
Okay.
So we're going to fetch that.
I'm sure.
Okay.
Here's, here's what we'll do.
Hopefully limit is hopefully that works.
If the dinosaurs at one, actually
we'll do this so we can print it out.
No, no, that's good.
We'll just go for it.
Okay.
It should be zero,
right?
Dinosaur zero.
Or do you want it to intentionally?
Yes.
You're right.
I, yeah.
Close call.
So we'll do this.
I see no reason why that wouldn't work.
Yay.
Okay.
So what dinosaur should, I guess
we should just look up Triceratops.
That's the coolest one, right?
Of course.
Triceratops.
How do you spell it?
Uh, tops.
If you know how to spell
Triceratops, you get a gold star.
Triceratops.
Cool.
Nice.
All right.
That was, uh, and not get
that didn't work at all,
but that's what did Michael say last week?
That's just a developer inability.
Yes.
Okay.
Just hard code Triceratops right
now, the path in the express.
Okay.
No, but it wouldn't
take it as a parameter.
I'm looking at the docs right now
and I'm not seeing it in there.
Where is it?
You'd think that this, oh, there we go.
Okay.
It is with, okay, that's my bad.
There we go.
Okay.
So we have node bond running,
so it's live reloading, so we
should be able to just hit it.
Bye.
Sarah Tops.
Hey, look at that.
That was quick.
And it's pretty quick.
Yeah.
Round trip 3 72.
Now granted the, it's
not making a call out.
Uh, I mean, it is running the,
the server locally, so we don't
have the network time for that.
But the round trip time for the
database neon, I got, if I run this
a couple of times, look at that.
I guess it's cashed.
It must be cashed because
it went from 376 to 150.
And then now all these are.
50 milliseconds, 100 milliseconds, 51, 51.
I'm assuming.
I guess the cache expired.
It must have a pretty low TTL.
I'm assuming people are connecting
because we got four connections.
And not just yours.
Oh, there's mine.
Let me kill mine.
Okay, I can kill mine.
Okay, so that, that worked.
That was cool.
Uh, let's do a join.
Let's see how it performs when
we, uh, when we do a join.
So let's do, what should we do?
What are the tables again?
I think I have the ERD somewhere.
You had it in.
Yeah.
Mermaid.
So we got species, taxonomy, naming.
I don't know what the meaning is.
Oh, named by who named the dinosaur.
Look at that.
Uh, period.
The mating.
Look up.
Can you fetch some of the data
from like the species table
so we can we can do that?
But what do you want if you're
gonna join you can join the dinosaur
with the species ID everything.
Oh, yeah, I guess
yeah Oh, yeah, but when we
actually go to test it is really
what I wanted to see what I need
to be able to look Up something.
Yeah, so I got the species here So
what do you want to get to which
which species was the triceratops?
Okay Species, species ID.
Okay, here we go.
Curly.
That's pretty close.
We'll start with that.
Select star from dinosaurs,
inner join species.
Is that, that's the name of the table?
Yes, where's, you want to
do it by name or by ID?
We're just gonna, uh,
we're gonna do it by ID.
Do I have access to your postman?
No, I don't.
Really?
I'll send you a name in the chat.
Libratus.
And it's been a long time since,
uh, I've written any sequel.
I know this isn't right.
As far as like, do line breaks and stuff.
Uh, okay.
Equals, I guess it's species ID.
Underscore ID, right?
That's what it's called
everywhere?
It's species underscore ID.
And then let me look at dinosaur.
It is species underscore ID.
Yeah.
Okay, so we'll do this.
That look good to you?
Where species name?
Okay, yeah.
Hopefully it's not a one to one because
then it's going to be so unexciting.
Where did you, where did you send the
species type that we're going to look up?
In the private chat here.
Okay.
I'll send two so we can
test two different ones.
Libratus.
Okay.
Well, that was fast.
Let's see how many there are.
Here, let's, let's change that so
I don't have to keep doing that.
So we will, we'll do count dinosaurs.
length and then we will
do dinosaurs as an array.
That looks good.
Let's run that again.
Okay, so there's two dinosaurs.
That's really nice.
I think Celestiae will have more.
That's 248 milliseconds.
Yeah,
it's
pretty
good.
So go try the other one.
I mean,
other
one.
Yeah.
I think that one has more.
Okay.
Cause that was ID one.
Nope.
I lie.
One,
one.
Yeah.
I don't know the count.
I guess I could just run.
I guess I could just do that.
I can make one of these
end points in here.
Oh no.
And just get the species
and print those out.
Close this off.
So select all from species.
Yeah,
there you go.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
I see
what you're doing.
Good restful practices is what I'm doing.
Oh no.
Okay.
What did we do wrong?
Selected you did from dinosaur
and you're joining species.
Yeah,
I don't know.
Let's Let's see if that resulted in
an error I guess I don't have any
tries try catches, but I I would have
assumed something would have printed out
Something should have happened here.
And I'm wondering if, actually,
now Okay, this is This is my bad.
Here.
This is an express thing.
Let's define that one before
we Oh, order mat, okay.
Order mat?
It's
matching on the first one?
Nope, lied.
Hey, worth a try.
I don't know.
I don't know why that wouldn't It doesn't
look like it's even making it in here.
Huh?
Facing.
Okay.
Well that's, that's fascinating.
Do, I'm just gonna restart.
I'm gonna restart express and
turn it off and turn it back on.
That's, that's the way to go.
Yeah.
Getting some good facts.
Wonderful.
Um, wonder why that doesn't work.
I guess it doesn't really.
Okay.
So we put this in
Lambda.
Yeah.
We try to get this lambda.
I think that's.
But you should pop up the, uh,
The Great Fact by BeriberiDK.
Can you pop it open in the screen?
Yeah.
Humans live closer to the time of
the Triceratops, and the Triceratops
lived to the time of the Stegosaurus.
Look at that.
Whoa!
That changes my whole way of living now.
What?
I feel like the magic school
bus lied to me when I was a kid.
I'm confident I remember those
two interacting with each
other in that dinosaur episode.
I mean, I, I, I only believe what
I see in Jurassic Park, alright?
Uh, the new ones.
Were they both in, were they
both in there in Jurassic Park?
Jurassic Park wasn't time traveling
though, that was a let's just take
all the dinosaurs that ever, ever
were and shove it all on an island.
That's true, that's true.
Taking their DNA, they, they got their
DNA from Doctor, I can't remember
his name, from the little bee, or
the mosquito, you remember that?
I'm going to have to rewatch
it.
Yes.
From the mosquito and the Amber.
Yep.
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's get it.
Lambda is what we were doing.
Uh, let's do that.
Okay.
Let me bring this side
now back to index JS.
I think we can actually do most of this.
Like wholesale inside of Lambda, but
I'm going to, I don't, I guess we don't
need a secret with this because we're
already exposed this time and time again.
Um,
hopefully you don't think that way,
uh, in your job, it's already exposed.
Let's just put it everywhere.
It's fine.
I actually don't know what to do here.
So we're going to see, we're going to see
on the fly, how to, how to make this work.
I don't know.
I don't know what to do.
I've never done a Lambda
function with express.
I don't think this is it.
I really don't think this is gonna be
it, but we'll No, I think it all has to
be defined inside of that main handler.
I'll get you, uh, I don't know, but I
know it doesn't seem to handler.
There's a serverless HTTP
package that we could use.
Interesting.
So did I do it right?
Did I do the list and inside
of the main execution?
Start server.
Let me see where this
start service being called.
I'm just looking at an example.
No, it's just starting server at the root.
And then there's a handler
with another handler.
It's exporting a handler.
And then, no, I don't like this example.
I'm going to go ahead and
do the initial deploy.
Yeah.
Everything seems to be using, so let me
go in the file, Alan, and I'm going to
Add some code that's commented so I don't
break your stuff that you're trying to do.
So I'm an app JS.
Where are you?
API JS.
I'm all over the place.
Okay.
You're already building Sam.
Might as well.
Index handler.
You didn't name the file index.
You named it API.
Okay.
You've got a functions index.
I see.
I see you.
Okay.
So I'm going to.
Go ahead and deploy these things.
I don't want to confirm changes.
Yes, let Sam create the role.
It's not disabled to roll
back something failed.
Yes, that's fine.
It has no auth.
And
yes,
let's save that.
Please don't follow us for guidance on
security practices in this live stream.
We're not here to be secure.
But somebody following this is
like, ah, okay, let's just put it.
I just want to make sure that's
not the standard practice.
What file are you in?
What file are you messing around in?
Uh,
API JS.
I put something in the bottom.
I didn't want to mess up the Lambda
function while you're deploying.
Oh.
Okay.
So you can get an example there.
Serverless HTTP.
That's a new
one for
me.
Both examples that I opened
from Google use that.
So,
Okay, works for me.
Let me install what I need to install.
npm install express and
serverless http and at neon
database slash serverless And that'll
be cool if this works, first try.
Second, maybe?
I'm not gonna, I'm not gonna try it.
Okay, I'll follow
CloudFormation on my end.
Where do I have that?
Okay,
so you have this.
Okay.
Let me go ahead and do that.
Look at all the stuff
that we're learning today.
Dino API.
Is it?
Yeah.
Let's roll back, dude.
The function URL does not exist in schema.
Function
URL does not exist in
schema for Lambda function.
Oh.
Oh no.
It's
just code URI and handler, right?
So
there's code URI.
I really thought that was it.
Oh, do I not have?
No, I have the transform on there for Sam.
You got, but handler.
Okay.
It is index.
Why is it?
Where's function URI?
It's just
output that I'm, that I'm looking for.
Oh, I swear this worked before.
This worked on another build that I did.
I was just trying to make it so I
didn't have to go into the console
to get it, but I mean, I'm fine.
I'll get it for you.
Looking at the docs for the intrinsic
functions or the return values.
Still issue.
Okay.
I'm, I'm okay with that.
So we have this, I'm going to
piece together all the things that
we've done before that we have.
It might be, uh, and, and the
believe in serverless chat.
There's, I just created
that account today.
And remember there's some limitations
when you initially start an account.
I don't know if this could be, I don't
know if function URLs might be one of it.
I don't know.
I feel like this is my skeptical face.
I'm trying to make sense if it
worked for you before, but I don't
see any return value from the
documentation on the function resource.
Okay.
I'll just take it out and then
we'll just have you look it up.
And we can use that.
So we'll just take out that output value.
What's the point.
And let me add this real quick.
So in index, this is our function handler.
We need to, what are we, what
are we piecing together here?
Okay.
I'm gonna use this as a reference.
We're going to see, I don't
think it's any different.
No.
Looks the same.
Oh, you fixed that.
I didn't want to bring that up,
but it was bothering me so much.
I
am shocked you didn't
call me out on something.
I had it.
Are you?
Oh, like, just keep going.
It's fine.
I'm I'm concerned why this one, or
I'm concerned that this one isn't
working, but I guess it is what it is.
So that looks then like it
should be right, so let's try it.
I'm keeping, I'm keeping track of
the metrics to see if at some point
something interesting happens.
RAM seems pretty standard.
Oh, we got up to five connections.
Now we're down to two, probably, or one.
Yeah, I guess if I took long
enough, it would have gone
idle.
And that's a good task.
We can talk about a story or something.
So it winds down and it goes idle and
get, see how much the cold start is.
Like a double cold
start, really?
Because you'd have the
cold start from Lambda.
And the cold start from Neon.
It didn't seem like it was slow when
we were doing it through the console,
but I guess that's all relative
anyway.
What's slow and what's not.
Let me check the, so right
now the main is, is idle.
Okay.
I really like the music.
So I had to delete the stack because I got
a failed deployment on the initial deploy
and it was in like rollback complete
and it won't try again in that state.
This is one of the features I
really, really want from
CloudFormation is just auto delete
on rollback if it's the first deploy.
It's usually a big issue and mostly
with ephemeral sandboxes where it fails
because we were playing around with it.
So, yeah, that's it.
It's going to fail at some point,
but I just wanted to auto delete.
So someone, I don't need to give
access to the console to someone to
delete the stack or something, because
we're doing everything from GitHub.
Um, so it's just weird.
You know, I'm really just not happy
that I can't figure this one out.
It doesn't look like, like,
I don't know.
Okay.
Go look up those, what that function
URL
is and we'll hit it,
please.
It's finished applying.
Okay.
Resources API function.
Where does it give you the function URL?
There it is.
Function URL.
It's there in the chat.
Yeah, I didn't, I didn't share
it in the public chat, right?
Okay.
And you're just gonna
paste it there, yeah.
Yeah, that's what it is.
Uh, we're gonna try species
and we're gonna see if, if this
one works, see what happens.
Oh, uh, it seems like, uh, 502 usually
is access denied, but Do you have
the event on the lambda function?
No, this is a function URL, so
it's not going through API gateway.
What was the
dinosaur name?
Let's dinosaurs.
Let's try a different endpoint
in there and see if that
gives us anything different.
Triceps.
Yeah, got my triceps going.
There we go.
I'm going to jump into logs at my end.
Okay.
So I guess that means we can't
say that we got it first try.
That's okay.
Internal server error.
Uh, reference error.
Neon is not defined.
Uh, we did not define neon.
Oh.
Okay.
You mean this?
Oh yeah, that would be a problem.
Whoops.
And this is, uh, this is the fun
part about doing things live.
Okay, so that will import Neon.
Okay, cool.
So I'm going to go back to Postman,
and I'm going to do Species.
And we're just going to get a list.
But that's not even the right,
that's not the right thing.
Dang it.
I'm going, I'm going back
to the local version.
Because this should really just
be Select Star from Species.
Yeah,
um, not that, it still doesn't
explain why nothing was coming back.
So you can rename dinosaurs to
species if you want to be correct.
No.
That's the, that's, okay.
This is the one that
wasn't working before.
This is really just doing a select all and
everything and it should have been, yeah
okay so it has the species name in here.
Um, okay, that worked!
Hey, we did it!
We created a landelit
because we can also do, yes.
I wasn't raising my hand, I was going
to point at my screen but it's the,
uh, It automatically, I guess they
have some web sockets or something.
I'm in the branches list and
it automatically showed active.
Uh, I didn't have to refer.
I wasn't going to refresh
to see if it was active now.
Um, so when you made that query, it
automatically went active for me.
And it wasn't, I mean, it, it didn't
come back slow.
It was, uh, at this
point I'm already passed.
I already did another commands.
Dang it.
But you, you can go to the console
and see the history of your requests.
Yeah.
Can you do that in VS code?
I think there is.
I don't see it.
Oh, just go.
There should be postman console.
There isn't a terminal area.
There's a postman console.
There you go.
Ooh.
Okay.
So that was, that was, uh, Yeah.
All right.
So that one was probably less than
ideal, uh, a second and a half.
Now this is.
The
Lambda was already, no, you just
deployed the Lambda function.
So let me get the.
That was definitely a cold start on that
one.
Let's run it again.
Let's, well,
I guess we can.
Lambda function to close
to 800 milliseconds total.
Okay.
Hold on.
Bill, an iteration was 353
milliseconds for the Lambda function.
So still quite, quite a
hefty.
So that one was half a second
to pull a response back.
Second call was 373.
Next call, it doesn't seem to be, I
mean, it's getting a little faster, but
it seems to be normalizing around three.
Let me see if there's cache hits.
Right, we're doing the same query.
So I wonder if that package, the
Neon package, is doing some sort of
caching somewhere, but the metrics,
the monitoring, uh, does deadlocks.
Nothing shows in the
caching portion of this.
No deadlocks, database size.
I kind of want to hit
this with a bunch of load.
I want to, I want to see what it does.
Yeah.
And another test we can do,
Alan, is one with a hot Lambda.
We can change the connection
to the dev one that I have.
That's idle right now.
Uh, and see what happens.
See what happens to the response time.
Yeah.
Just to, okay.
Now intentionally we're idle.
Yeah.
Okay.
Cool.
Let's do this then.
I don't think I can, let's
create a new collection.
Let's see, do you get a query
log on the neon console?
Let me, let me check that out Sam.
So, overview, I'm gonna navigate and
if I find it I can share my screen.
There's the usage.
It doesn't look like I have access
to the load testing capabilities
of Postman from inside of VS code.
But that's fine.
I'll just open up.
I'll just open it up
and we can share that.
I just created a collection,
so it should be available.
So we'll, we'll walk through,
there's a lot of integrations
that they offer already.
Uh, good to take a look there.
I don't see anything, Sam, in
regards to like history, I see
start compute, suspend compute.
So I can see, Oh, look at, okay, Alan, let
me do, I guess you have my screen there.
We can pop it open.
Uh, it does.
So Sam, it doesn't keep a log
of all the queries that happen,
but more infrastructural stuff.
So you can see the start compute.
Uh, I'm mounted time.
So at 2.
19, which lines up probably when
you, the successful query went
and we can get, uh, it's, it took
159 milliseconds to start up.
So the startup plus the query, and that's
where I don't know where we can get those
metrics on query performance, right?
Um, we could add metrics and the
Lambda function to pump out metrics or
observability or segments and traces
and stuff to better calculate that.
Okay.
On the query itself.
Okay, we're going back to So postman real
quick, that is, let me see how to zoom in.
Okay.
There we go.
So I have just the, the list
endpoint in this collection.
I can do multiple.
I don't think it's necessary,
but I'm going to do the
performance test simulator.
I'm going to say, you know, if we run
up money on your free account, this
is, this is what does it, uh, let's do
Pete.
They don't have my
credit card, so I'm good.
Just, just do it.
Simulate a fixed load for
four users for two minutes.
Then no fix it.
Okay.
So we're going to pretend like
there's 20 people hitting this API and
then we'll see what happens 20
virtual users repeatedly running the
collection in parallel for two minutes
sound good Let's see my connection count.
All right now you can't hear it,
but my laptop now sounds like a jet
engine As it has spun up all these
processes hitting this end point.
It seems to be doing okay though,
I mean it's pretty consistent.
There was a big one, what's the
spike there at the beginning?
That was probably the
cold start time, 492,
yes this was sending, okay right now
it's sending 12 requests a second.
Connection count just went
boom, just went all the way up.
Right now it's at five from one, but it's
taking, it's taking a second to catch up.
Oh, you're sharing again.
Okay, cool.
So here is the connection count.
So you can see the big spike
right now with your stuff.
Um, everything else seems
pretty stable though.
Let's see, RAM still pretty low.
You can see a
slight.
Boost?
Does it show anywhere like peak
stuff like what it got up to?
Doesn't seem to be anywhere
just like hey look at this.
Um this is last hour so connection
counts you can see here six.
So this to me makes me think it's reusing.
Did you define the connection
outside of the handler?
It did.
Okay, so it's probably
reusing connections.
Why it's not super spiky.
Should we try to break it?
And yeah, sure.
Try to, yeah.
All right, let's do that.
So here's, and something I wanted to
point out this, these integrations, right?
So you can, um, you can see with
Vercel, Polyscale, but like for
logging, uh, you can send the logs
to Datadog, New Relic, Sentry, they
have like tools on top of this, not
going to go too deep into this, but.
it might get more information out of
the metric logs and stuff that you
want um out of this so you can see
cypress github but go put the connection
inside of the handler so we can get 12
connections per second see what happens
Okay, so what I am going to do, I
think I'm still sharing Postman.
So let me, let me switch back to VS code.
So performance.
Yeah, cool.
So I'm going to create a new
endpoint just called break.
And what I'm going to do in here
is I guess we'll initialize SQL 2.
And just do the dinosaurs query.
No, I want to join all the tables.
Okay, I like it.
Okay, so we're going to do.
Select star from dinosaurs, D.
Can you tell me what the
table names are?
So we got species, hold on, period.
Species ID, right?
Species ID is on both dinosaur
and, and then we got join period.
What else?
Give me the table names
period period name.
Oh,
oh, I thought you were telling me
a period on Okay, uh, all right
classic That's pretty funny.
That's like a Wait,
wait, period is period ID
in that.
Okay.
All right,
and then D and the from the
dinosaur table It's also period ID.
Okay, what else?
Then we got location, where it's
location underscore ID on location
table and location underscore
ID on the dinosaur table.
Oh, you gave me the nice
intuitive naming convention.
So then naming has naming ID.
Naming?
Like this?
It's who named it.
Who named the dinosaur.
Uh, I, do we know?
I'm gonna And actually, Alan,
we don't have a, we don't have
that field on the dinosaurs.
So, ignore that one.
We don't have a way to join.
Okay, what else?
Anything else?
Location, naming periods,
species, taxonomy.
It's taxonomy ID and taxonomy
underscore ID on both.
Oh, I just spelled it twice in a row
without making it a mistake, which
means, you know, that's about to happen.
It's going to work.
I hope.
Oh no.
I thought I was going to misspell
it when I was doing the joint.
Okay.
Uh, so we have that.
No reason to not just run that, right?
Well, you got to return it.
Yeah.
Count and then dinosaurs.
Cool.
You are using SQL too.
Okay.
Yeah.
Sam build, Sam deploy.
Let's do that.
Okay.
So that's just running a big join
across everything that will get cached
and that's probably also not like
a super heavy query to run anyway.
I'm not seeing anything in
the cache monitoring, like
any cat buffer cache hit rate.
There's nothing there.
So what do you think is
going to happen here?
If I just do a, without doing a load,
because we're going to hit it first,
just to make sure that it actually does
something.
I feel like we're gonna get 429s or
something that I'm exceeding my free tier.
I don't know how many connections
the free tier gives me.
It's probably limited, but it
doesn't say anything about it.
So
I'm wondering then if that's the case,
I don't know if this throws an exception
or if this does, like, if this returns
an error, uh, so I'm like Postgres
directly because you're running SQL, but
we're using neon, so I'm assuming there's
some sort of wrapping around errors.
I would hope from a
package provided by them.
Uh, like.
Regularly, if like box API, right?
If you use their SDK, they
have standard retries.
When you hit four to nine with
backoff built into the SDK,
similarly to AWS SDK, right?
So I would hope there's some sort
of handling internally for that.
You would hope
I would hope
you never know though.
I mean, they just went GA like,
well, is it Tuesday this week?
Wednesday this week?
And, you know, it's, it's not going
to be completely feature complete
like you would see in the references
that you were just describing.
Probably not anyway.
Okay.
So, Sam, we're trying the, we're burning
the world before we want to live in it.
Uh, so his suggestion
to, yeah, there it is.
There was a toggle to enable
socket pooling on the console.
But we're going the other way around.
We're trying the Do you
want me to turn that on?
I can turn that on.
Let me see.
It's already off, right?
Yeah, so if you switch to my screen,
it's adds a pooler flag to the
connection string, but we would need
to change the connection string.
Do you want to try that,
Alan, or do you want to?
We can change it in a minute.
Let's change it in a minute.
I want to, I want to see what
happens if we just do it as is.
Cool.
Right now, because yes, I do, I
do want to do that and see how it,
see the difference that it makes.
Okay, so the
main branch is currently active, right?
So it's still active,
so we'll not hit that.
I mean, we're not trying to get
the cold start time right now,
so it worked.
Yep, so that was one, 1.
29 seconds.
Round trip, let's hit it again.
456.
Ooh.
Okay.
But look at the, like all the
handshake and all that stuff.
It's taking quite a bit.
Transfer start.
But yeah, still not ideal.
Like on my normal day to
day, that's probably fine.
You know, we're trying to
shoot for lower than 1.
5 seconds.
So it's still under the expected,
but for more critical workloads,
800 milliseconds might be.
I agree.
You're also going to have to, I mean,
keep in mind, this is just the API side.
Like when you're talking about app
development, you're still going
to have to wait for the content
to render in your user interface.
And I mean, it's not a ton of
records, but it is still 309
records with a lot of data in it.
We could pad that and see
if there's not no time.
Okay.
I'm going to, I'm going to switch
back to postman real quick.
Uh, so here's your screen.
Are there any analytics that we want?
Okay.
So let's see the monitoring.
Let's get the latest there.
Everything pretty stable.
As far as Ram, you can
see the connection peak.
We got the one, I guess, from the
request you just did database size,
nothing that just catches my eye.
So we're still the same, same boat here.
Okay.
So you feel good?
I'm going to switch back.
Okay.
Yeah.
I need to update this collection.
Break it.
Okay.
I'm going to just test to make sure, okay.
We do get a response.
All right.
So let's go back.
I think that I have opened in here.
Okay.
This we're going to,
you did not say the request, by the way.
Yeah.
It turns out I was editing
the request inside of VS code.
Not in
funny.
Okay.
Uh, This close, click on the
collection, run performance tests.
Here we go.
How many does it let me do?
Do a hundred.
I have a developer machine.
Test duration, two minutes.
Okay.
We have lift off my laptop.
I learned my lesson from last
week when it completely crashed.
I put a book.
Underneath it, like right in the middle.
So there's at least air that can get to
the fan a little bit easier underneath.
Oh yeah.
I have my laptop lifted
with a little stand.
How many requests have come through?
Uh, a thousand, but look, we started off
with errors probably when it was scaling.
Interesting.
I'll I'll see if I can search
anything in the Lambda function.
How good are you with.
Uh, CloudWatch
insights, not how are we pumped?
I just do add message, like error and
look something for something like that.
That's
fine.
Like we're still getting them.
Interesting.
So it's trying to scale again.
I don't see any, like
the connection count.
Oh, there it is.
We're up to 10.
It's getting there.
So let me go to log insights over here.
So this is hitting, this is hitting Neon
with, you can see right here on Postman,
it was, you know, averaging 64 ish
requests a second, which isn't that bad.
That much.
I don't know.
I guess
that's all.
That's very relative.
It's very subjective.
But what is that many?
I wouldn't expect the service
to be failing at that if
it's touted as serverless.
I guess.
Yeah, there you go, Andres.
It's a 429.
It is.
I imagine.
But I don't know what f429 is coming from.
Is that coming from the function
URL or is that coming from Neon?
Because it shouldn't it was coming
from Neon then I wrapped that in a
500 should have been returning a 500
I guess it's gonna take a
while to get to Log insights.
I'm still saying just a neon not defined
Let's take a look at the monitoring
dashboard We capped at 10 connections,
which is, is that a limit?
And like how many we have,
we actually see something, there's
more of the CPU being used, but
still under the 25, this is still
at the same and no other peaks.
Let me refresh one more time.
So it doesn't tell me anywhere.
If there's a limit to how many
concurrent connections you can have.
Uh, as far as the free tier, but it
seems to me like it's capping it at 10.
Yep.
Interesting.
It's funny that it says idle
10, but not truly total idle.
None of them show active.
I don't think this is.
Um, yeah, that might
not be, that might not
be accurate.
And something I just realized just now.
Is we're just testing read capacity.
All we're doing is fetching data.
We're not doing anything with
inserts or update on data at all.
But yeah, you can see as the test done.
Yeah.
You
can see, cool.
So it was probably the two minutes.
Yeah.
And so we 4, 000.
850, uh, total requests.
So I'm going to guess that
that 429 or the set of 429.
So let me see the breakdown.
If it has that in postman, um, I'm
going to guess it doesn't have it.
That those came from the function URL.
Well, it's a gamble and man, I
think it probably was that like
that might've been Lambda scaling.
I'm not getting much exit error.
Uh,
what are you looking at right now?
Trying to get, uh, errors
from the cloud insights.
I can put this tab.
Oh, okay.
And you can see it.
So here I, okay.
So, so bright.
Ooh, man.
Is there a dark mode for cloud watch?
Let's see.
There should
be.
I didn't think it was
specifically CloudWatch.
I thought it was like the whole
console you could turn into dark mode.
They started doing like one by one and
then I don't know if they did them all,
but oh well, not while you're here.
So I'm trying to get anything where
error, run time, exit error, and
this is the neon and not defined.
So
I'm not getting any new ones from.
So we're trying to find something
closer to our timestamp.
They're not flowing in yet.
Okay.
So in the meantime, while we
wait for that, cause that's not
fun to watch, uh, I'm going to
check metrics for Lambda.
Okay.
So Sam is saying if the
Fortune 9 is Lambda.
We won't see them in the logs,
but we would see them here.
Oh, okay.
So yeah, we got throttle
83 throttles from Lambda.
So yeah.
Good call, Sam.
Nice.
Well, another thing that we learned
today, that was very useful.
Yeah.
Nope.
Here are the errors.
Cool.
Okay.
So how about we do this?
Let's test right.
Has to be.
That's fun.
Yeah.
Now I am not going to be brave enough
to try to create new dinosaurs with
referential integrity and all that.
I, we only have like 15
minutes left on the stream.
So what we can do instead is I'm going
to create this post the slash species,
and we're just going to create a new
one with the value that was passed in.
Sound good.
I like that.
Cool.
And then.
I'd really like it if it had the
ID, if it came back with the ID.
We'll see, right, with the
import we provided the ID,
so I haven't done an insert.
I don't know if it's auto incrementing
that ID for us, you know what I mean?
I do know what you mean, and I also don't
know, so we'll, we'll try and we'll see.
Is it?
Yeah.
Let's find out why don't you
actually, you know what, let's just
go right now to the neon console.
Why don't you just run
that command and we'll see.
Can you send me the command?
If it does that, yeah.
Uh, so I will send you the command.
And you can
I guess it's just Insert into species
And then In parenthesis, species
name Species underscore name Okay,
I need to species underscore name.
Yep.
Uh, and then after that,
nope, nope, leave it.
And then values.
Man, I don't remember any of this.
And then in parentheses, uh,
whatever you want to call it.
Yeah, sure.
We'll call it test.
Uh, sure.
All right.
Let's see.
Okay.
Oh, it does not have that annoying.
Then we'll have to modify that with the,
I think it's 310.
Let me check that.
All right.
So we've got species.
Yeah.
SQL editor run one query.
Okay, great.
So, okay,
I'm going to, let me flip back to my,
to my good real quick, and then we have
that and then we'll do, I guess we'll
do like a loop.
Just do a loop.
I'm just going to do random.
Yeah.
It's, what
is it?
Do you remember, do you remember,
um, how to use math dot random?
Why don't you let CodePilot
or CodeWhisperer take it up?
Okay, all right, const
generatedId equals math.
random.
I really thought I was going to do that.
Okay, that's fine.
It's math.
random, and you can specify range, right?
Yeah, we're just going to say times a
million, and we're going to hope that
that doesn't collide with anything.
Cool.
When you did that in the console,
did you pass in an integer?
Right?
It wasn't a string, right?
Yeah, it was an
int.
Okay.
Okay, so what we'll do is we
will skip that out of here
and then inside of postman,
pcs, hosts, body, raw, json, name, Random.
There's usually IntelliSense on this.
Check postman.
Random name or something.
I
think they have something like random
nonsense that we could probably
use or like random business name.
Dynamic variables GUID.
Random UUID.
Boolean.
Boolean abbreviation.
IP.
Lookout.
Protocol.
Job area, job type.
There's not like random BS.
Business database, domains, files
and directories, stores, grammar,
randoming, random ing verb,
random adjective, random word.
Oh, but it's not random enough, honestly.
Random word.
There's random text.
I updated the wrong
file, I have to redeploy.
It's annoying.
Yeah, there's a random word.
Postman.
Okay, then what's the,
what's the UUID one?
Let's do that.
UUID is random UUID I'm assuming.
I'm going to search random UUID.
Yeah.
Oh, and I'll pass, right?
Okay, so we'll, we'll save
that, we'll see if that works.
So we'll be creating a new species, and
hopefully, it's gonna give us a 200 VEC.
Sorry, I forgot to
change the status to 201.
Oh, Alan.
You know what I'm gonna do?
While that's deploying, I'm gonna
change that status to 201, so
you don't, uh, get really mad.
And then next time, when we
inevitably have to make a change,
that status will be a 201.
Sweet.
Okay.
Ah!
That sucks.
What did we do?
I want to make sure that we actually
sent Did we actually send a random UUID?
No.
Oh, wait.
These are with Maybe that's
why I didn't get IntelliSense.
That's why I didn't get IntelliSense.
I was using string interpolation.
But we also got One million is too much.
We got an, uh, integer out of range.
Is
that good?
I guess so.
Can't count zeros that fast.
So let's try it.
One, two, three.
A million is too much.
We Three, two, three, four, five.
I mean, it's not too much
for integer out of range.
No, no, that, that should work.
Okay.
And on the bright side, you know, I
probably did that on purpose because now.
It's going to deploy and return the
201 on create instead of the 200.
I knew that was going to bother you
and we weren't going to be able to
claim this as a successful test until
it returned the right status code.
Okay, so that's going to go
I need to just get rid
of this window, this one.
There we go, okay.
So frustrating to see that
internal service error.
Will you want to try
Yeah, it's returned the error.
No, it wasn't.
It was neon, right?
Hopefully you have a schema
validation on your APIs or something.
That's
weird.
That's a good, that's not an integer.
Yeah, now I don't know what to think.
I have no idea what to think now.
Let me look at the neon console.
See what the data looks like.
It was species, right?
Yeah.
Um, assume it's so the species
name was undefined and we got
5, 2, 4, 4, 4, 9, 3 as the ID
that you're saying we're just passing in.
Okay.
Maybe this is no?
Let me look at the I don't, I don't
think we're printing the event.
Maybe it's a dollar sign?
Oh, it's yeah, let me check.
This sounds like another skill issue.
It's curly bracket, curly,
curly bracket, dollar sign.
Yes.
Okay.
Definitely skills.
Thank you.
Hey, I was here.
I didn't catch it.
So I played both of us.
You got an ID though.
We're not doing a null check.
We're not doing a null check
on the lambda function.
So wait, I'm sorry, did you
say the ID was an integer?
Did it get parsed to an integer?
Yeah, so the
ID is 524.
It's the first part of that.
Yeah.
And so it didn't error on us
when we passed that into it.
Okay.
No.
So it actually, I mean, it actually
saved, but the species name is undefined.
Okay.
So then we'll, we'll update
this one really quick.
Uh, okay.
Let's send that.
Okay, so we got that.
Let me, let me refresh on my end.
Okay, I'm gonna, I'm gonna
share your screen real quick.
Oh, I still have mine.
Is it?
But it's still loading, it's putting
data in there, so we can still test
the, even with our lack of SQL skills.
Of,
of all things.
Well, I, that must be a data issue, or
like, that's a code issue then, because
it did actually pass, uh, a UUID in there.
Uh,
yeah, nobody, you You don't
have the post doesn't have a
name and oh, it's in the body.
Oh,
well, honestly, it doesn't matter.
What we want to see is how it handles
a bunch of rights at the same time.
So let's do that real quick.
And that's probably the
last thing that we do.
We can do that and then try and
get nailed down a pulling one.
But if we're out of time, it's fine.
Oh, yeah, we can do that.
All right, let's do this real quick.
All right, postman, break
it, which is now post.
And we're gonna be passing that in.
Mark says rest purist.
Yeah, that's me.
Okay, runs.
Nope, run performance, uh, fixed.
We'll do 100 again for two minutes.
Let's see what the rides do.
Last one you did a thousand.
No.
Didn't you?
I was pretty sure it was a hundred.
No, I couldn't have been a thousand.
Well, the Lambda function
executed a thousand times.
Here's the peak.
Let's see what this does.
Let's see if we get a similar result.
And then afterwards, I'm going to
go back in this recording and watch
it and send it, send the code.
But do you that shows that
I did a hundred me wrong?
Yeah, I don't know.
Okay.
Let me go back to the neon console
and I'll keep track of this.
So we started with errors or
29 we expected is that scaling.
The interesting thing here is Lambda.
Is scaling.
Well, Lambda is preventing us from
hitting the neon database so much, right?
Because it's taking a while to scale.
So initially neon is fine because
Lambda is not scaling as fast, but once
Lambda is up, up to scale, would it,
would now neon be the one that fails?
I don't know.
So this is much, much faster
than the get, which makes sense.
We're also reusing the connection again,
I forgot to declare that every time.
I forgot that we had practice.
Oh yeah, I got
8 connections.
Still kind of capping at 10, so it
feels like we're still Connection
count just went to the bottom.
Did we kill it?
No, it's still going.
It says it has a decent
amount of time left.
Okay, now it's back up.
Fast.
Real fast.
Do all these inserts.
Woo!
Rose!
Rose spiked in my graph
if you want to show.
So here's Rose.
We have 2, 910.
Yeah, we've just added 8, 500 species.
Probably all undefined names,
but just with different IDs.
And let's see the RAM CPU.
This is spiking up a little
bit too, but not concerning.
I see Mark.
Yes.
Usually I try to hide the 500s and
return a 200 with the status code.
Um,
I just returned a 400 and
say, it was probably you.
There should be like a question
mark, uh, status codes.
Like who was it?
We don't know.
So we're at 5, 000, but everything's
hopefully in the future.
There's like the, I want to see
kind of like the Lambda monitoring
where you see throttles and stuff,
because I don't know if we're actually
going to get throttled or not.
Right.
And I don't know.
He has a spike, probably the max.
Okay.
It's winding down as
far as connections go.
5, 000.
Is it done?
It handled it really well.
Now granted, it was a rea those were
really small rows that we were adding.
Yeah.
We're just testing.
But it did, it did handle that.
What were we sending?
We were sending 76 requests
a second on that write.
I think these, this graph malfunctions
every now and then, and it shows zero,
it's like I'm like, did it finally die?
And no, I think it handled it well.
Yeah, so the, no new records coming in.
What do you want to do next, Alan?
Do you want to try the, I
guess we're at two hours now.
Nah, we
gotta, we gotta wrap.
Yeah.
We are, we are at time.
So that was, I think it did really well.
It did.
All things considered,
like actually using it.
And now granted, we were
not writing production code.
We weren't even pretending to write
production code, but as far as like
Lambda is concerned, I really think the
implementation, maybe we just shoved
that connection string in a secret.
Yeah.
Cause it's giving you everything
and it's giving you, it's
giving it to you, protect it.
So now you can abstract it secrets.
That's a set for Ram.
Even environment variable if you want
but that's it to get it into a lambda.
So that's nice.
I agree I I agree and so, you know
the trade off there Well, that is much
nicer We're gonna say that I've never
used Aurora But I do know that Aurora
requires a VPC around that lambda
function to connect to it And that was
a lot easier than setting up a VPC.
So, you know, big fan of that.
Um, it seemed to scale okay.
At least the apps that you and I wrote
together in years past, we never really
got to 76 requests a second every second.
And we might have peaked past that.
But, you know, uh, on
average, it was okay.
Um, I, the, I can't, I still can't
in my heart say that I feel like
it's truly serverless given the
The way that it's priced and the
rate, the way that it's billed.
Um, but if
you're currently managing a
database, it's managing more
than what you're used to, right?
Yeah.
And again, the VPC part and all that
stuff, it's like back to, it's maybe
serverless is strong of a word there, but
like the open search debacle, it's like,
it's still better, it's still handling
more, but it's still not full serverless.
It's more managed.
It's what I call those
more managed.
Yeah, that's, that's a
fair, fair assessment.
You know, I want to see, I want to,
I want to mess around with it more.
We probably won't do it on the show, but
I want to mess around with it more and
work with it in a way that's not prone
to SQL injection attacks, uh, where I'm
not just writing the SQL command and then
just doing string interpolation of the
things that came in off a query parameter.
Uh, for obvious reasons, right?
Um, I do want to see like
the right way to do it.
Uh, but
probably, probably stamp some
observability on top of it and get
the real metrics, uh, around every
piece of this to see how much truly
is neon versus Lambda cold start
versus if it's hot, right, just
getting those metrics would be good.
And one of the things that we didn't
really mess around with, and I don't
even know if it was a thing was the.
access management.
Like, I don't know if we can generate
different connection strings that
are read only versus write only.
There are roles.
So there is, there is a role.
There are, there is a role portion where
it's just, I'm trying one route right now.
So just to close that loop, it
gives you a different password.
Um, and you can download
it, but it doesn't seem to.
It doesn't seem to give you like
permissions, just read only versus right.
Um,
it'll probably get there.
Yeah.
Something to take, take a look at.
So overall, would you give it a
thumbs up or a thumbs down for
the service neon in general?
I, I like it.
It was simple.
You know, I've been out of the relational
world for a while and sequel and all that.
And then we were able to get.
Up to speed pretty quickly.
Um, and it's all managed for me so I
can easily, if I wanted to create an app
that uses this, I wouldn't be scared.
Me neither,
which I don't know how I feel
about myself saying that.
You know, I've just been no
sequel for, you know, since like
2018 or something like that.
Yeah.
Uh, but it's, it's good to
know that the tooling and the
services that are available today,
It seems to have a lot of integrations and
there's a lot of good stuff that can come
out of, for the CI CD pipelines, right?
As we mentioned, you can
branch out the branching thing.
That's.
Mind blowing for me.
That just seems, I never thought
about that, but that's pretty
cool.
It is cool.
Somebody said in, in the comments in
the beginning, when we were fangirling
over it is that it's a snapshot.
That's all it is.
Uh, and I mean, that's
not, that's not wrong.
It's branded in a much cooler way, which
made me as a developer, like, yeah,
sweet.
Well, I think it, it's mostly a user
experience on top of that then, right?
It's, it feels.
Just something that's not foreign to
me because I use GitHub every day.
I know how to branch my expectations
from that branch are different
because of GitHub, right?
I was expecting to be able to merge
that branch that it doesn't go that far.
I guess that's why they say one
of the two hardest problems in
computer science is naming things.
If you name it the wrong thing,
then it's like, Oh, it's just.
Snapshot, but name it a branch.
And it's like, Oh, I'm all over that.
Yes.
Okay, cool.
Oh, thank you everybody
for hanging around.
Uh, this has been, I, I learned a ton.
It's super fun.
A thumbs up for me, for Neon
and Postgres in general.
I did like that.
That was nice.
Uh, yeah, yes, thumbs, thumbs up.
Alright, cool.
Well, we'll see you guys next week.
Andres and I are gonna do this
pretty much every Friday, same time.
Uh, one, one o'clock
central, six o'clock p.
m.
UTC.
Uh, and I think, what
are we doing next week?
Next week, we're working
with step functions.
And we're going to be building
a summer vacation planner.
So we'll fill out a Google form and then
we'll expect an email, uh, very shortly
after that, that's going to give us our
itinerary, how much it's going to cost all
that, all that fun stuff using generative
AI, step function, the HTTP integrations,
all that, all that fun stuff.
I think that'll be good.
All right, cool.
So until then, everybody
have a good weekend.
Thank you for, uh, Europeans who are
watching us late on a Friday night.
Or probably really fun to watch
if you've been drinking, honestly.
Um, but anyway, Thank you.
Thank you.
Uh shout out special to uh,
serverless guru for letting us
use their dreamyard account.
Appreciate that Uh new sponsor
of believe in serverless.
So we appreciate you.
Jonathan's been behind
the scenes the whole time.
You can't see him Me saying his name
was my attempt to draw him out, but
it doesn't look like that's working.
So, uh, there he is.
There he is.
Yeah,
of course.
I even went to make sure I got my,
my stole this from my girlfriend.
So, you know, it doesn't even fit me.
I'm not even gonna show
you the rest of it.
That's like way too tight.
Yeah, I didn't have to mention that,
but you know, now that we're here.
Yeah.
Thanks a lot, Jonathan.
Of course.
I think it's our first successful one.
We'll see.
Yes.
Very successful.
That's awesome.
I'm looking forward to the next one, guys.
Thank you.
All right.
Yep.
Thank you.
All right.
Until next week.
See you guys.
See ya.
Adios.
Bye.